Lindsey Lauria

Address Irvine, CA 92603 Phone 714-552-9511 Email lijlauria@mac.com **LinkedIn** https://www.linkedin.com/in/lindseyjjlauria **GitHub** https://github.com/LindseyJeeJan **Website** https://lindseyjeejan.github.io/my-portfolio-react/

Summary

User-focused Front End Engineer with over 20 years experience in design and development of responsive and accessible user interfaces. Communicating effectively with both programmers and product stakeholders lends itself to creating the best user experiences while considering business requirements and resource budgets. Experienced in all phases front-end development from design deliverables, wireframing, rapid prototypes to clean, optimized production ready code.

Technical Skills

HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, Web APIs, REST APIs, Express, MongoDB, GraphQL, React, Vue.js, Vuex, Jest, Yarn, NodeJS, NPM, MySQL, OOJS, accessibility, WCAG 2.1, WAI-ARIA, Jira, Git repository, GitLab, CI/CD, Agile, Scrum, SDLC, rapid prototyping, interaction design, Sketch.

Work Experience

Front End Software Engineer, Accessibility Team • Perceptyx • Temecula, CA (Remote) • 11/2021 ~ Current

- Contributed to technical design and implementation of front-end of a SPA Vue.js application meeting WCAG 2.1 AA specifications. Migrated component library away Bootstrap by implementing native HTML elements and creating SCSS codebase independent of frameworks and/or libraries.
- Worked with team to establish code style guide for SCSS and Vue.js. Incorporated Git workflow best practices into team processes.
- Developed component library using Storybook in collaboration with design team and front end engineers to provide technical documentation and working code samples.
- Coordinated and led accessibility guild to evangelize accessibility standards within the organization and lead company-wide accessibility initiatives.

Senior Interaction Designer • Ultimate Kronos Group, Incorporated • Irvine, CA • 05/2012 ~ 11/2021

- Developed user-facing features for web and mobile enterprise application coded by hand in HTML5, CSS3 and vanilla JavaScript in an agile environment.
- Created and maintain visual design system while producing a large volume of reusable design components and responsive full page layouts using Bootstrap framework.
- Solved cross platform and cross browser display issues to maximize acceptance across supported platforms and browsers, performed cross browser testing in BrowserStack.
- Reviewed application improvements to ensure technology is utilizing the latest browser supported features. Performed iterative front end design reviews ensure development is completed on time and prevent costly code fixes.

- Lead, defined and implemented accessibility standards initiative through the translation of WAI-ARIA accessibility standards into technical tasks to conform to a WCAG 2.0 AA acceptance criteria.
- Participated in continuous collaboration with programmers, Product Managers and stakeholders
 to provide technical guidance for best practices on front end architecture. Evaluated technical
 considerations along with business requirements to recommend how to achieve a successful
 design within the time budget.
- Designed features in Sketch, produce wireframes, clickable prototypes and multiple deliverable formats for use across organization. Lead design presentations to clearly articulate concepts to technical and non-technical audiences.

Web Developer • Glidewell Laboratories • Newport Beach, CA • 08/2006 ~ 05/2012

- Coded and maintained corporate websites using search engine optimization and implementation of Google Analytics to measure traffic and visitor trends. Used Photoshop to extract digital print graphics and turn them into interactive, media rich websites with Adobe Flash.
- Developed front end of customer facing application along side team of programmers for an ASP.NET application using Microsoft TFS.

Education

California Polytechnic State University • San Luis Obispo, CA • 1997 ~ 2001 Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, concentration in Management Information Systems

UCI Division of Continuing Education • Irvine, CA • 2021 Certificate, Full Stack Developer

Department of Homeland Security Office of Accessible Systems & Technology Certificate, Trusted Tester (Section 508 Federal Accessibility Requirements)

Coding Projects

Home City

Home City is an SPA that allows the user to search for cities within the US to provide statistics that may be important criteria when deciding on a potential relocation. The application is built with MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, Apollo GraphQL, React-Bootstrap, Semantic UI React, Heroku and the Teleport API.

URL https://github.com/LindseyJeeJan/Home-City

Deployed Project https://ll-home-city.herokuapp.com/

Favor Trader

Favor Trader is a neighborhood bartering platform for favors. It contains an Activity Feed where all user's favors needs are listed. To begin trading, each user will need to log in or sign up and create a user profile. This application is built with Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Heroku, Bootstrap, Bootswatch, jQuery, and Google Maps API.

URL https://github.com/LindseyJeeJan/Favor-Trader

Deployed Project https://favortrader-ll.herokuapp.com/

Study Buddy

The application provides the user with the ability to gather learning resources and coding solutions for various learning styles by connecting to StackExchange and YouTube APIs. Uses REST APIs and JSON.

URL https://github.com/LindseyJeeJan/project-one

Deployed Project https://lindseyjeejan.github.io/project-one/